卡西利亚斯法师
Master Kaecilius.
那个仪式依我看只会害了你
That ritual will bring you only sorrow.
伪君子
Hypocrite!
来个有难度的 比利
Challenge round, Billy.
噢 比利 别跟我开玩笑了
Oh, come on, Billy, you've got to be messing with me.
没开玩笑
No, doctor.
如沐春风 查克·曼卓林 1977年
Feels So Good, Chuck Mangione, 1977.
说真的 比利 来个难点儿的
Honestly, Billy, you said this one would be hard.
- 是1978年 - 肯定不是
- Ha! it's 1978. - No, Billy.
虽然如沐春风是1978年上的排行榜
While Feels So Good may have charted in 1978...
但这张专辑可是1977年12月发售的
the album was released in December of 1977.
不 维基百科说
No. Wikipedia says it's a nineteen...
再查查吧
Check again.
你的脑子里怎么装了这么多没用的东西
Where do you store all this useless information?
没用
Useless?
这哥们儿凭一把小号就吹进排行榜前十了
The man charted a top 10 hit with a flugeihorn.
查好了吗 比利
Status, Billy?
1977年
1977.
- 果然是 - 真受不了
- Oh, please. - I hate you.
噢
Oh!
真是如沐春风 是不是
Feels so good, doesn't it?
我来接手 史蒂芬
Oh, I got this, Stephen.
你的任务完成了 撤吧 我们收尾
Youve done your bit. Go ahead. Well close up.
什么情况
What is it?
应该是枪伤
GSW.
他竟然还活着
it's amazing you kept him alive.
呼吸暂停 脑干检查
Apneic, failed the brain stem test...
和呼吸反应检查都失败
and the apnea reflex test.
我知道问题在哪儿了 帕尔默医生
I think I found the problem, Doctor Palmer.
还有颗子弹没取出来
You left a bullet in his head.
谢谢 可能是伤到了延髓
Thanks. it's impinging on the medulla.
我需要一位专家 尼克诊断他脑死亡
I needed a specialist. Nic diagnosed brain death.
可我真的觉得不大对劲儿
Something about that doesn't feel right to me.
那咱们得抓紧
We have to run.
韦斯特医生
Doctor West.
你在干什么 嗨
What are you doing? Hey.
取器官 他是捐献者
Organ harvest. He's a donor.
慢着 这事我还没同意呢
Slow down. I did not agree to that.
不需要你同意 已经确认他脑死亡了
I don't need you to. Weve already called brain death.
结论太早了 我们要给他准备枕下开颅手术
Prematurely. We need to get him prepped for sub-occipital craniotomy.
我不会让你在一个死人身上做手术的
Not gonna let you operate on a dead man.
你看这个
What do you see?
- 这是子弹 - 完整的子弹
- A bullet? - A perfect bullet.
加强过的
it's been hardened.
由金属铅和金属锑加强过的子弹
You harden a bullet by alloying lead with antimony.
是有毒合金 当其毒性直接进入脑脊髓液之后
A toxic metal. And that's leeched directly into the cerebral spinal fluid.
急性发病 中枢神经停止反射
Rapid onset central nervous system shutdown.
我们走吧
We gotta go.
病人是濒临死亡
The patient's not dead, but he is dying.
还要取他的器官吗
Still want to harvest his organs?
- 要不要我来帮你 - 不
- I'll assist you. - No.
帕尔默医生会帮我的
Doctor Palmer will assist me.
谢谢
Thank you.
马上进行影像导航
Image guidance, stat.
我看没时间了
We don't have time for that.
你不能直接上手
You cant do it freehand.
我当然能上手
I can and I will.
这可不是你炫耀的时候 斯特兰奇
This isn't a time for showing off, Strange.
是谁十分钟前宣布他已经死亡了的
How about 10 minutes ago when you called the wrong time of death?
颅内神经完好
Cranial nenies intact.
韦斯特医生 你手表声太大
Doctor West, cover your watch.
其实 你犯不着在众人面前羞辱尼克
You know, you didn't have to humiliate him in front of everyone.
我也犯不着去管他的病人
I didn't have to save his patient, either.
你知道 我就是有点情不自禁
But I sometimes just can't help myself.
尼克是个好医生
Nic is a great doctor.
可你找了我
You came to me.
我只是需要有人帮我做二次诊断
Yeah, well, I needed a second opinion.
你早就有二次诊断了
You had a second opinion.
你要的是更权威的诊断
What you needed was a competent one.
你就当我随时待命的神经外科医生吧
Well, all the more reason why you should be my neurosurgeon on call.
你可以拯救很多生命
You could make such a difference.
我可不进你那个屠宰场
I can't work in your butcher shop.
嗨
Hey!
更何况我做的是断裂脊髓融合
I'm fusing transected spinal cords.
是刺激中枢神经系统再生
I'm stimulating neurogenesis in the central nervous system.
我的工作在未来能会拯救上千人
The work I'm doing is gonna save thousands for years to come.
在急救室 你救的是拿着枪的醉汉
In ER, you get to save one drunk idiot with a gun.
对 你说得没错
Yeah, youre right.
在急救室里我们只能忙着救人
In ER, were only saving lives.
没名气 也没有 电视台采访
There's no fame, there's no, uh, CNN interviews.
看来我还是跟尼克凑合好了
I guess III just have to stick with Nic.
不 等一下
Whoa, wait a minute.
你们俩 不会是已经
You're not... You guys aren't...
什么
What?
那样了吧 抱歉
Sleeping together? Sorry,
我觉得我已经把意思表达清楚了
I thought that was implicit in my disgust.
嗨嗨嗨 说清楚哪样了
Explicit, actually.
我的原则是绝对不和同事约会
No, I have a very strict rule against dating colleagues.
是吗
Oh, really?
我叫管这叫斯特兰奇原则
I call it the Strange Policy."
真好 能有以我的名字命名的东西很好
Oh, well, good, I'm glad somethings named after me.
你知道 我首创了椎板切除术
I invented a laminectomy procedure.
为什么就是没人愿意把它叫做斯特兰奇术
And yet, somehow no one seems to want to call it the "Strange Technique."
是我们一起创立的这项技术
We invented that technique.
是 不管怎么说 你的那个原则让我受宠若惊
Regardless, I'm very flattered by your policy.
我要在今晚神经学协会举办的晚宴上演讲
I'm talking tonight at a Neurological Society dinner.
和我一起去
Come with me.
有演讲要演 还真是浪漫
Another speaking engagement? So romantic.
你不是挺喜欢和我浪漫的吗
You used to love coming to those things with me.
那会儿我们多开心
We had fun together.
不 只有你开心而已
No! You had fun.
那些事只对你有好处
They weren't about us, they were about you.
不仅是对我吧
Not only about me.
史蒂芬 这世界是围着你转的
Stephen. Everything is about you.
把咱们的名字连在一起
Maybe we could hyphenate.
斯特兰奇-帕尔默技术
Strange-Palmer Technique.
我的名字应该在前面
Palmer-Strange.
比利
Billy.
有什么需要我的
What have you got for me?
我这儿有一位35岁的空军上校
I've got a 35-year-old Air Force Colonel..
低位脊椎被某种实验装置压碎
crushed his lower spine in some kind of experimental armor.
胸椎中段爆裂性骨折
Mid-thoracic burst fracture.
好吧 这个我能做
Yeah, well, I could help...
而且你随便找谁都能做
but so could 50 other people.
给我找点刺激的 别浪费我时间
Find me something worth my time.
我这儿还有一个68岁的女性
I have a 68-year-old female
患有晚期脑干胶质瘤
with an advanced brain stem glioma.
你想毁了我一世英名吗
Yeah, you want me to screw up my perfect record?
我才不要呢
Definitely not.
还有个22岁的女性
How about a 22-year-old female...
脑部被植入电磁仪器 用来控制精神分裂症
with an electronic implant in her brain to control schizophrenia...
结果被闪电击中了
struck by lightning?
嗯 这个听起来有点意思
Mmm. That does sound interesting.
能给我发一下
Can you send me the...
收到
Got it.
嗨
Hey.
没事 一切都会好起来的
it's okay. it's gonna be okay.
他们给我做了什么
What did they do?
他们用直升机送你来的
They rushed you in a chopper.
花了很多时间才找到你
But it took a little while to find you.
可是你已经错过了
The golden hours for nerve damage went
治疗神经损伤的黄金时间
by while you were in the car.
他们给我做了什么
What did they do?
十一根不锈钢钢钉插进了骨头里
11 stainless steel pins in the bones.
多处韧带撕裂
Multiple torn ligaments...
双手神经严重损伤
severe nerve damage in both hands.
手术整整持续了十一个小时
You were on the table for 11 hours.
看看这些固定器
Look at these fixators.
没有人能做得更好了
No one could have done better.
我可以做得更好
I could have done better.
不
No.
你得耐心等待身体恢复
Give your body time to heal.
你彻底把我给毁了
You've ruined me.
需要多久我才能
How long until I can take...
斯特兰奇医生
Doctor Strange.
那些软组织还在恢复中
Those tissues are still healing.
那加个速
So, speed it up.
用支架从肱动脉进入桡动脉
Pass a stent down the brachial artery into the radial artery.
可能行
it's possible.
虽然是实验阶段 而且价格不菲 但可行
Experimental and expensive, but possible.
我需要的就是可行
All I need is possible.
往上抬
Up.
往上
让我看到你的用力
Show me your strength.
这根本没用
This is useless.
有用 哥们儿 你可以的
it's not useless, man. You can do this.
你老实回答我 本科高材生
All right, answer me this, bachelors degree.
你见过神经损伤这么重
Have you ever known anyone with nerve damage
用这个治疗方法
this severe to do this...
最后还能恢复的人吗
and actually recover?
还真有一个
One guy, yeah.
工伤事故 背部受伤 瘫痪
Factory accident, broke his back...
一条腿彻底残废
paralyzed, his leg wasted away.
坐在轮椅上 他肩膀都疼
He had pain in his shoulder, from the wheelchair.
他每周来做三次康复
He came in three times a week.
后来就不来了
Then one day he stopped coming.
我以为他死了
I thought he was dead.
几年后在街上 他从我身边走过
A few years later, he walked past me on the street.
- 走过 - 是啊 没错
- Walked? - Yeah, walked.
胡扯 我要看他的医疗记录
Bullshit. Show me his file.
你以为调医疗记录那么容易吗
Itli take me a while to pull the files from the archive.
能让你这自负的混蛋闭嘴
But if it proves your arrogant ass wrong...
也值了
Worth it.
听着 我看了你所有的研究
hooked at all your research..
阅读了你提供的所有文献
I read all the papers you've sent.
这根本行不通
It's not gonna work.
你可能都没明白
I don't think you realize...
- 你伤得有多重 - 听我说 我想说的是
- how severe the damages are. - Here's the thing...
现在连最好的医生都无力回天了
The best have tried and failed.
是 我 我明白 只是问题在于我
I understand. Heres the thing.
说真的 这件事我帮不了你 史蒂芬
What you want from me is impossible, Stephen.
行了
Come on.
我得为我的名誉着想啊
I've got my own reputation to consider.
- 别这样 艾迪安 等等 - 我真的帮不了你
- Etienne, wait. No. - l can't help you.
不 不 等等
No, no, wait!
嗨
Hey!
他不愿意
He won't do it.
庸医
He's a hack.
在东京有种新技术
There is a new procedure in Tokyo.
他们培育升级供体干细胞
They culture donor stem cells... and then harvesting them
然后用三维打印染色体骨架
and then 3D printing a scaffold.
可是我得先筹一笔钱
If I could get a loan together...
史蒂芬
Stephen.
不多 费用才二十万
A small loan, just$200,000.
史蒂芬 你总是赚多少钱就花多少钱
You've always spent money as fast as you could make it...
你现在完全就是在透支啊
but now youre spending money you don't even have.
是不应该考虑放弃了
Maybe it's time to consider stopping.
不 不 现在绝对不是该放弃的时候
No, now is exactly the time not to stop...
你看到了 我根本就没有好起来
because, you see, I'm not getting any better!
你现在已经不是在治病了
But this isnt medicine anymore.
又何必执着呢
This is mania.
有些事你是无能为力的
Some things just can't be fixed.
没有事业的人生
Life without my work...
那也是人生啊
Is still life.
又不是世界末日
This isnt the end.
总会有别的东西让你的生命充满意义
There are other things that can give your life meaning.
比如什么 你
Like what? Like you?
你现在应该向我道歉
This is the part where you apologize.
你现在应该转身离开
This is the part where you leave.
好吧 反正我已经看不下去你这个样子了
Fine, I can't watch you do this to yourself anymore.
你看不下去了 是吗
Oh, too difficult for you, is it?
是的
Yes, it is.
我难受 看到你这样我的心都快碎了
It breaks my heart to see you this way.
不要你可怜我
No, don't pity me.
我没有可怜我
I'm not pitying you.
那你来这儿干嘛
Oh, yeah? Then what are you doing here...
带着奶酪和红酒 好像我们是要去野餐的老朋友
bringing cheese and wine like we're old friends going for a picnic?
我们根本不是朋友 克丽丝汀
We are not friends, Christine.
也谈不上恋人
We were barely lovers.
你就喜欢看悲剧
But you just love a sob story, don't you?
你看我就是个悲剧嘛
Is that what I am to you now?
可怜的史蒂芬 看他多可怜
"Poor Stephen Strange, charity case."
他终于需要我了
"He finally needs me."
又一个社会的弃儿需要你拯救
Another dreg of humanity for you to work on.
用心开导开导
Patch him up and send him back into the world...
再重新开始人生
heart's just humming.
你高兴得恨不得唱起歌来 是不是
You care so much, don't you?
再见 史蒂芬
Goodbye, Stephen.
史蒂芬·斯特兰奇
医疗报告
告诉过你了
潘博恩·J  2014年12月9日 大都会综合医院
- 快传球 - 这边
- All the way. - Here we go.
好的 太漂亮 了
Let's go! All day! All day!
好球
Yeah! All day.
加油啊 哥们儿 多好的比赛
Come on, manl Where's the competition?
真是话唠
Talk a lot.
乔纳森·潘博恩
Jonathan Pangborn...
颈7颈8两段脊髓完全损伤
C7-C8 spinal cord injury, complete.
你是谁
Who are you?
胸部以下瘫痪
Paralyzed from the mid-chest down.
双手部分也已经瘫痪
Partial paralysis in both hands.
我不认识你
l don't know you.
史蒂芬·斯特兰奇
I'm Stephen Strange.
神经外科医生 曾经是神经外科医生
I'm a neurosurgeon. Was a neurosurgeon.
我想起来了 哥们儿 我还真认识你
Actually, you know what, man, I do know you.
我去过你的办公室 你连见都不见我
I came to your office once. You refused to see me.
你助理那关我都过不去
I never got past your assistant.
我根本救不了你
You were untreatable.
你那叫知难而退 对吧
No glory for you in that, right?
你从绝望中找到了希望 还创造了奇迹
You came back from a place there's no way back from.
我 我也在试着创造我的奇迹
I'm trying to find my own way back.
嗨 潘博恩 还还玩不玩了
Pang born, are you in or you out?
好吧
All right.
我当时已经想放弃了
Id given up on my body.
我以为只有我的大脑还在正常运转
I thought my mind's the only thing I have left...
那应该让它锻炼一下
I should at least try to elevate that.
我和一群法师圣女在一起学习
So, I sat with gurus... and sacred women.
一群陌生人抬着我上山 面见圣人们
Strangers carried me to mountaintops to see holy men.
最终
And finally...
我找到了我的导师
I found my teacher.
我这儿进入了全新的境界
And my mind was elevated...
我的灵魂也得到了升华
and my spirit deepened.
然后 不知怎么
And somehow...
你的身体就痊愈了
Your body healed.
是的
Yes.
那里还有很多奥秘
There were deeper secrets to learn there...
但我没有足够的精力继续学习了
but I didn't have the strength to receive them.
既然奇迹已经降临 我就决定乖乖地回家了
I chose to settle for my miracle and I came back home.
你要找的地方叫做卡玛泰基
The place you're looking for is called Kamar-Taj.
但去那儿很贵
But the cost there is high.
要多少钱
How much?
这个和钱无关
I'm not talking about money.
祝你好运
Good luck.
来继续 传球
Let's ball. All right, ball up!
尼泊尔 加德满都
呃 卡玛泰基
Uh, Kamar-Taj?
你知道卡玛泰基在哪儿吗
You know where Kamar-Taj is?
喜马拉雅治疗所！找到安宁！ 找到自我！
卡玛泰基
Kamar-Taj?
Kamar-Taj.
噢 天呐
Okay.
不好意思 各位 我 我没有带钱
Look, guys, I don't have any money.
手表给我
Your watch.
不 别这样 我 我只剩下这块表了
No, please. it's all I have left.
把手表给我
Your watch.
好吧
All right.
你在找卡玛泰基
You're looking for Kamar-Taj.
这儿
Really?
你确定是这儿吗
Sure we got the right place?
那个地方才更像 卡玛泰基
That one looks a little more Kamar-Tajey.
我也问过同样的问题
I once stood in your place.
我那个时候也不怎么懂礼貌
And I, too, was disrespectful.
我能给你点建议吗
So, might I offer you some advice?
忘掉你自以为知道的
Forget everything you think you know.
好吧
All right.
这儿是我的师父的圣殿
The sanctuary of our teacher.
她叫古一
The Ancient One.
叫古一
The Ancient One?
是真名吗
What's his real name?
好吧
Right.
忘掉自以为知道的 抱歉
Forget everything I think I know. Sorry.
呃 谢谢 噢
Urn, thank you for... Whoa!
好吧 真是谢谢
Okay, thats a thing.
谢谢
Thank you for...
你好
Hello.
噢 谢谢
Oh, thank you.
非常感谢
And thank you.
呃 谢谢
Uh, thank you...
谢谢你接见我 古
Ancient One, for seeing me.
你不用那么客气
You're very welcome.
这位是古一
The Ancient One.
谢谢你 莫度法师 谢谢 哈密尔法师
Thank you, Master Mordo. Thank you, Master Hamir.
斯特兰奇先生
Mr. Strange.
呃 是医生 我是医生
Uh... Doctor, actually.
其实你已经不再是医生了
Well, no, not anymore, surely.
所以你来到这儿
Isn't that why you're here?
你最近做了很多手术
You've undergone many procedures.
七次 对吧
Seven, right?
是的
Yeah.
茶很不错
it's good tea.
是的
Yes.
你曾经治愈了一个叫潘博恩的人
Did you heal a man named Pangborn?
一个瘫痪的病人
A paralyzed man?
算是吧
In a way.
你帮助他能够走路了
You helped him to walk again.
是的
Yes.
你是怎么把完全损坏的颈7颈8两段脊髓给治好的
How did you correct a complete C7-C8 spinal cord injury?
不是我治的
Well, I didn't correct it.
他走不了路 我说服他可以走
He couldn't walk. I convinced him that he could.
你不会说那是心理治疗吧
Youre not suggesting it was psychosomatic?
当你重新连接受损的神经时
When you reattach a severed nerve...
是你在治疗 还是肢体在自愈
is it you who heals it back together or the body?
是细胞
it's the cells.
但是细胞只会通过
The cells are only programmed...
其本身独特的方式进行复原
to put themselves back together in very specific ways.
没错
Right.
如果我告诉你 你的身体可以
What if I told you that your own body could be convinced...
说服自己进行各种形式的复原呢
to put itself back together in all sorts of ways?
难道你是在说细胞再生吗
Youre talking about cellular regeneration.
这可是非常前沿的医疗技术
Thats bleeding edge medical tech.
所以你要这里研究
Is that why youre working here?
因为没有医学会的监管
Without a governing medical board?
我想问一下 这方法研究得怎么样了
Just how experimental is your treatment?
还行
Quite.
这么说 你找到了
So, youve figured out a way...
让神经细胞重新自我修复的方法
to reprogram nerve cells to self-heal?
不 斯特兰奇先生
No, Mr. Strange.
但是我知道怎么借助灵魂
I know how to reorient the spirit...
更好地治愈身体
to better heal the body.
灵魂治愈身体
The spirit to heal the body?
没错
That's right.
不 好 好吧
No. All right.
那我们该怎么做
How do we do that?
从哪儿开始
Where do we start?
- 喜欢这张图吗 - 噢 不
- Don't like that map? - Oh, no.
很好 但是我之前只在
it's really good. It's just, I've seen it before...
礼品店见过这个
in gift shops.
那这个呢
And what about this one?
- 针灸 太棒了 - 是吗
- Acupuncture, great. - Yeah?
那么这个呢
What about that one?
给我看核磁共振图像 我不相信你这个
Showing me an MRI scan. I do not believe this.
这些图是手工画的
Each of those maps was drawn up by someone...
正如盲人摸象 只见其树木 未见森林
who could see in part, but not the whole.
我倾家荡产 买了这张单程票
I spent my last dollar getting here, one- way ticket...
您现在跟我说 得靠信仰来治愈
and you're talking to me about healing through belief?
你是个从洞中看世界的人
You're a man looking at the world through a keyhole.
你一生都在尝试
You've spent your whole life
把这个洞弄得更大点儿
trying to widen that keyhole...
从而见多识广
to see more, to know more.
可如今知道这个洞能再大点儿
Now, on hearing that it can be widened...
大到你无法想象时
in ways you can't imagine...
你却拒绝这种可能性
you reject the possibility.
我拒绝是因为我不相信 什么器官脉轮的神话故事
No, I reject it because I do not believe in fairy tales...
也不相信什么精神力
about chakras or energy...
或者信仰的力量
or the power of belief.
根本就不存在什么灵魂
There is no such thing as spirit!
人类是物质的 仅此而已
We are made of matter and nothing more.
你也只是这宇宙中的一粒
You're just another tiny, momentary speck
微小而无关紧要的尘埃而已
within an indifferent universe.
你太小看你自己了
You think too little of yourself.
噢 你觉得你已经看透我了
Oh, you think you see through me, do you?
是这样吗
Well, you don't.
其实是 我已经看透你了
But I see through you!
你刚才对我做了什么
What did you just do to me?
我把你的灵魂推出了你的身体
I pushed your astral form out of your physical form.
茶里放了什么
What's in that tea?
裸头卓碱 迷幻药
Psilocybin? LSD?
就是茶
It's just tea...
加了点蜂蜜
with a little honey.
刚才怎么了
What just happened?
一瞬间 你进入了一个灵魂世界
For a moment, you entered the astral dimension.
什么
The what?
就是灵魂脱离了身体的所到之处
A place where the soul exists apart from the body.
你为什么要这样对我
Why are you doing this to me?
告诉你未知的东西太多了
To show you just how much you don't know.
睁开你的眼睛
Open your eye.
噢 该死
Oh, shit!
噢 天呐 噢 天呐  不
Oh, God! Oh, God, no!
不 不 不
No, no, no!
发生了什么
What's happening?
这不是真的 这不是真的
This isnt real!
再这样 他的身体会承受不住的
His heart rate is getting dangerously high.
我觉得他还好
He looks all right to me.
你自以为谙晓世事运行
You think you know how the world works?
你还以为物质宇宙就是一切
You think that this material universe is all there is?
什么是真
What is real?
在你所认知的背后 还藏着怎样的秘密
What mysteries lie beyond the reach of your senses?
在现实的源头
At the root of existence...
精神会与物质相连
mind and matter meet.
思想雕琢了现实
Thou ghts shape reality.
噢
Oh!
这个宇宙只是无限宇宙中的一个
This universe is only one of an infinite number.
世界是无限的
Worlds without end.
有的美好 生机勃勃
Some benevolent and life giving.
有的邪恶 充满了杀戮
Others filled with malice and hunger.
在那些黑暗的角落
Dark places...
蛮荒之力在贪婪地
where powers older than time lie ravenous...
伺机等待
and waiting.
你是谁
Who are you
在这多元宇宙中
in this vast Multiverse,
斯特兰奇先生
Mr. Strange?
你在礼品店里见过这些吗
Have you seen that before in a gift shop?
教我吧
Teach me.
不
No.
No!
不 不 不
No, no, no!
不
No!
开开门 拜托
Open the door! Please!
有劳各位了
Thank you, Masters.
你觉得我不应该把他赶出去
You think I was wrong to cast him out?
已经五个小时了 他还在门口等着呢
5 hours later, he's still on your doorstep.
他身上有一股劲儿
There's a strength to him.
倔强 傲慢 还有野心
Stubbornness, arrogance, ambition.
似曾相识
I've seen it all before.
他让你想起了卡西利亚斯
He reminds you of Kaecilius?
我可不想再让一个有天赋的学生
I cannot lead another gifted student to power...
入门后被黑暗吞噬
only to lose him to the darkness.
但你没有失去我
You didn't lose me.
我渴望获得力量 去打败敌人
I wanted the power to defeat my enemies.
是你给了我力量 消灭心魔
You gave me the power to defeat my demons.
你让我学会遵循自然的法则
And to live within the natural law.
心魔不会被消灭 莫度
We never lose our demons, Mordo.
我们只学会了与他们共存
We only learn to live above them.
失窃的那几页还在卡西利亚斯手上
Kaecilius still has the stolen pages.
如果他破解了其中的奥义 他会把我们
If he deciphers them, he could bring ruin...
全部消灭
upon us all.
黑暗势力日益强大
There may be dark days ahead.
或许斯特兰奇能帮卡玛泰基渡过难关
Perhaps Kamar-Taj could use a man like Strange.
别把我关在外面
Don't shut me out.
我现在哪儿都去不了了
I haven't got anywhere else to go.
谢谢
Thank you.
泡个澡
Bathe.
休息一下
Rest.
有时间的话
Meditate...
冥想一会儿
if you can.
稍后古一会传唤你
The Ancient One will send for you.
香巴拉
这是什么 我的咒语吗
Whats this? My mantra?
这儿的无线密码
The Wi-Fi password.
我们又不是原始人
Were not savages.
时间会告诉你 我有多么爱你 克丽丝汀
克丽丝汀
这神秘法术的语言
The language of the mystic arts..
自诞生文明起就一直存在
is as old as civilization.
还在很久以前
The sorcerers of antiquity...
尊者们把这种语言称为咒语
called the use of this language 'spells.'
如果这名字让你觉得不太现实 那就
But if that word offends your modern sensibilities...
将其理解为程序
you can call it a 'program.'
搭建现实世界的源代码
The source code that shapes reality.
我们收集能量
We harness energy...
从多元宇宙的其它空间里获取
drawn from other dimensions of the Multiverse...
念出咒语
to cast spells...
铸造出盾牌
to conjure shields...
和利器
and weapons...
从而施展法术
to make magic.
但是 即便我的手指可以做到这些
But even if my fingers could do that...
我的手还只能在空中摇摆
my hands would just be waving in the air.
我的意思是 怎么从菜鸟到大师
How do I get from here to there?
那么你是如何修复好受损的神经
How did you get to reattach severed nerves...
如何将断裂的脊椎拼回原位的
and put a human spine back together bone by bone?
勤学加苦练 年复一年
Study and practice, years of it.
嗨
Hey.
斯特兰奇先生
Mr. Strange.
呃 请叫我史蒂芬
Uh, Stephen, please.
- 你是 - 王
- And you are? - Wong.
王
Wang.
是真名
Just Wong?
像阿黛尔
Like Adele?
或者亚里士多德
Or Aristotle.
德瑞克
Drake.
博诺
Bono.
埃米纳姆
Eminem.
这是视之书
The Book of the Invisible Sun.
这是宇宙新编
Astronomia Nova.
至尊法典
Codex Imperium.
所罗门之钥
Key of Solomon.
这些你都读完了
You finished all of these?
是的
Yup.
跟我来吧
Come with me.
好的
All right.
这个区域只对法师开放
This section is for masters only...
不过我同意的话 其他人也可以来看
but at my discretion, others may use it.
你可以从基础总论开始看
You should start with Maxim's Primer.
你梵文怎么样
Hows your Sanskrit?
反正有在线翻译
I'm fluent in Google Translate.
吠陀语 最古老的梵文
Vedic, classical Sanskrit.
那些是什么书
What are those?
那些是古一的私人收藏
The Ancient Ones private collection.
所以不能借阅
So, theyre forbidden?
在卡玛泰基 知识是可以共享的
No knowledge in Kamar-Taj is forbidden.
但有些并不能实践
Only certain practices.
这里除了至上尊者之外
Those books are far too advanced
其他人根本看不懂那些书
for anyone other than the Sorcerer Supreme.
这本书少了几页
This ones got pages missing.
这是卡里奥斯特罗之书
Thats The Book of Cagliostro.
是研究时间的
A study of time.
其中有几页被原来这儿的一个法师偷走了
One of the rituals was stolen by a former master.
狂热者 卡西利亚斯
The Zealot, Kaecilius.
他用绳子把前任图书管理员挂了起来
Just after he strung up the former librarian...
让他身首分家
and relieved him of his head.
我现在是这些书的守护者
I am now the guardian of these books.
但凡这些书有任何的缺页少皮什么的
So if a volume from this collection should be stolen again...
我都会知道
I'd know it...
我会让你还没出门 就身首分家
and you'd be dead before you ever left the compound.
要是过期未还呢 或者
What if it's just overdue?
我需要了解少一页 会缺胳膊少腿吗
Any late fees I should know about? Maiming, perhaps?
以前大家都觉得我还挺逗的
People used to think that I was funny.
你给他们开工资
Did they work for you?
真高兴和你聊天儿
All right. Well, it's been lovely talking to you.
感谢你介绍这些书
Thank you for the books...
和令人毛骨悚然的故事
and for the horrifying story...
以及对我的各种威胁
and for the threat upon my life.
我们现在接受那些
We will now receive the power
可以摧毁背叛我们
to destroy the one who betrayed us.
以及整个世界的能量
The one who betrays the world.
熟练使用悬戒在法术中十分重要
Mastery of the sling ring is essential to the mystic arts.
它可以帮我们自由穿行于各个宇宙
They allow us to travel throughout the Multiverse.
你需要高度集中精力
All you need to do is focus.
使其形象化
Visualize.
脑海中浮现你的目的地
See the destination in your mind.
不要局限于眼前的世界
Look beyond the world in front of you.
要想象出每个细节
Imagine every detail.
脑海里的画面越清晰 传送之门
The clearer the picture, the quicker and easier...
就会出现得越快
the gateway will come.
先停一下
And stop.
我想跟斯特兰奇先生单独谈谈
I would like a moment alone with Mr. Strange.
请吧
Of course.
是因为我的手
My hands.
跟你的双手无关
it's not about your hands.
怎么可能跟我的双手无关
How is this not about my hands?
哈密尔法师
Master Hamir.
谢谢你 哈密尔法师
Thank you, Master Hamir.
抽刀断水水更流
You cannot beat a river into submission.
你得学会顺势借力
You have to surrender to it's current...
仿佛这力量源于你本身
and use it's power as your own.
顺势还怎么控制
I control it by surrendering control?
这根本就是行不通的
That doesn't make any sense.
世间万物自有其自身的道理
Not everything does. Not everything has to.
你靠自己的聪明才智获得了成功
Your intellect has taken you far in life...
但仅此而已
but it will take you no further.
觉悟吧 史蒂芬
Surrender, Stephen.
放弃你的自我
Silence your ego...
力量才会强大
and your power will rise.
跟我来
Come with me.
等等
Wait.
- 这是 - 珠穆朗玛峰
- Is this... - Everest.
非常美
Beautiful.
是 没错 很美
Yeah, right, beautiful.
真冷 但是很美
Freezing but beautiful.
在这种温度下
At this temperature...
人如果待上30分钟以上
a person can last for 30 minutes...
身体器官 包括性命 会发生危险
before suffering permanent loss of function.
好极了
Great.
你可能还扛不到两分钟就会晕倒
But you'll likely go into shock within the first two.
- 什么 - 屈服吧 史蒂芬
- What? - Surrender, Stephen.
不 不
No!
他表现怎么样
How's our new recruit?
几秒之内
We shall see.
即刻见分晓
Any second now.
还用这样吗
Oh, no, not again.
我是不是应该
Maybe I should...
史蒂芬
Stephen.
王
Wang.
你想要什么
What do you want, Strange?
我要关于灵魂出窍的书
Books on astral projection.
你还没有准备好
You're not ready for that.
试试看喽 碧昂斯
Try me, Beyoncé.
噢 天呐 你应该听过吧
Oh, come on. You've heard of her.
她可是个巨星
She's a huge star, right?
你毫无反应
Do you ever laugh?
噢 拜托 给我看看
Oh, come on, just give me the book.
不
No.
就在这间屋子里
Once, in this room,
你曾经求着我教你
you begged me to let you learn.
现在你告诉我 你质疑所有的课程
Now, I'm told you question every lesson...
选择自学
preferring to teach yourself.
在这间屋子里 你曾经让我开拓视野
Once, in this room, you told me to open my eye.
现在却让我盲目接受一些
Now, I'm being told to blindly accept rules...
完全没有道理的规矩
that make no sense.
是指不让你在图书馆随意使用悬戒的规矩吗
Like the rule against conjuring a gateway in the library?
王打小报告了
Wong told on me?
法术方面 你确实学得很快
You're advancing quickly with your sorcery skills.
你现在需要个更安全的地方练习
You need a safe space to practice your spells.
这里是镜像空间
You are now inside the Mirror Dimension...
虽然存在 但无法察觉
ever present but undetected.
这儿发生什么都与现实世界无关
The real world isn't affected by what happens here.
我们在这镜像空间里训练 监视
We use the Mirror Dimension to train, surveil...
有时也用来隔离危险
and sometimes to contain threats.
如果没带悬戒 你会被困在这里
You don't wanna be stuck in here without your sling ring.
等等 不好意思 你指的危险是什么
Hold on. Sorry. What do you mean, "threats?"
想要了解无尽的多元宇宙 也要了解其无穷的危险
Learning of an infinite Multiverse includes learning of infinite dangers.
如果我现在告诉你 你不知道的一切
If I told you everything else that you don't already know...
你肯定会被吓跑的
you'd run from here in terror.
她到底有多大岁数了
So just how ancient is she?
还没有人能知道至上尊者的年龄
No one knows the age of the Sorcerer Supreme.
只知道她是凯尔特人 从没提过她的过去
Only that she's Celtic and never talks about her past.
这么不知根知底 你还跟着她
You follow her, even though you don't know?
我知道她坚定不移 严格善良
I know shes steadfast... but unpredictable.
尽管深不可测
Merciless, yet kind.
她造就了我
She made me what I am.
相信你的师父
Trust your teacher...
别误入歧途
and don't lose your way.
就像卡西利亚斯
Like Kaecilius?
是的
Thats right.
你认识他
You knew him.
他刚来这里的时候
When he first came to us...
已经一无所有 生无所恋
he'd lost everyone he ever loved.
他伤心欲绝 渴望从神秘的法术中寻找答案
He was a grieving, broken man searching for answers in the mystic arts.
他天资聪颖 他骄傲固执
A brilliant student, but he was proud, headstrong.
他质疑古一 他甚至拒绝古一对他的教导
He questioned the Ancient One, rejected her teaching.
他离开了卡玛泰基
He left Kamar-Taj.
他的追随者像绵羊一样跟着他走了
His disciples followed him like sheep.
他们被虚假教义所蛊惑
Seduced by false doctrine.
就是他偷的那些书页 是不是
And he stole the forbidden ritual, right?
是的
Yes.
那几页是什么
What did it do?
你就别再问了
No more questions.
什么意思
What's that?
这也算问
That's a question.
这是法器
This is a relic.
有些魔法太难驾驭
Some magic is too powerful to sustain...
所以我们将其注入于物体
so we imbue objects with it...
这样才能随时让我们运用自如
allowing them to take the strain we cannot.
这是 我们使用的
This is the staff...
生命法庭权杖
of the Living Tribunal.
法器各不相同
There are many relics.
瓦图魔杖
The Wand of Watoomb.
这个 瓦尔托的跳跃靴子
The Vaulting Boots of Valtorr.
这名字还不是一般的拗口
Really just roll off the tongue, don't they?
- 我什么时候可以有法器 - 你准备好的时候
- When do I get my relic? - When you're ready.
噢 我准备好了
I think I'm ready.
那得由法器决定你是否准备好了才行
You're ready when the relic decides you're ready.
现在
For now...
用法术当武器
conjure a weapon.
好吧
All right.
战斗
Fight!
生命危在旦夕 战斗
Fight like your life depended on it.
终有一日
Because one day...
必将如此
it may.
克丽丝汀
我再次给你写信
王
Wong?
好吧
Okay.
首先 打开阿戈摩托之眼
'First, open the Eye of Agamotto."
挺好
All right.
噢 天呐
Oh, my.
要是我
What if...
多玛姆
'Dormammu.'
黑暗空间
'The Dark Dimension.'
永恒的生命
Eternal life?
- 什么 - 住手
- What the... - Stop!
你怎么能这样随便打乱时空界限
Tampering with continuum probabilities is forbidden.
我 我刚才只是按照书里说的做的
I was just doing exactly what it said in the book.
书里说了什么
What did the book say
那有没有提到这样做的危险
about the dangers of performing that ritual?
我不清楚 我还没有看到那部分
I don't know. I hadn't gotten to that part yet.
要知道时间操控术可以创造时空分支
Temporal manipulations can create branches in time.
那是个极不稳定的空间
Unstable dimensional openings.
空间悖论 时间循环
Spatial paradoxes! Time loops!
你想被困在无限反复的时间里
You wanna get stuck reliving the same moment
永世不得脱身
over and over forever...
或者从来没有出现过吗
or never having existed at all?
警告是不是应该印在咒语前面才对
Really should put the warnings before the spell.
你的好奇心会让人丧命
Your curiosity could have gotten you killed.
你刚才那样做并不能操控时空
You weren't manipulating the space-time continuum...
而是在破坏它
you were breaking it.
我们不能扰乱自然法则
We do not tamper with natural law.
要捍卫它
We defend it.
你刚才是怎么做到的
How did you even do that?
嗯
Hmm?
你从哪儿学的这么冗长的咒语
Where did you learn the litany of spells required to
还居然能明白
even understand it?
我可有过目不忘的能力
I've got a photographic memory.
不然怎么能获得医学和物理学博士
That's how I got my M.D. and Ph.D. at the same time.
但是你刚才那
What you just did...
光靠记忆力可做不到
takes more than a good memory.
你天生就是神秘法师
You were born for the mystic arts.
但是我的手还是不听使唤
And yet my hands still shake.
只是暂时的
For now, yes.
不是永久性的
Not forever?
我们不是预言家
Were not prophets.
你打算什么时候告诉我真相
When are you gonna start telling me what we are?
像复仇者那样的英雄们
While heroes like the Avengers
保卫世界不受自然侵害
protect the world from physical dangers...
像我们一样的法师们 保护世界不受魔法侵袭
we sorcerers safeguard it against more mystical threats.
至上尊者的名号代代传承
The Ancient One is the latest in a long line
古一是现任
of Sorcerers Supreme...
上千年前的神秘法师祖就是强大的
going back thousands of years to the father of the mystic arts...
阿戈摩托
the mighty Agamotto.
他创造了阿戈摩托之眼 就是你刚才打开的那个
Same sorcerer who created the eye you so recklessly borrowed.
阿戈摩托在现代城市中创造了三个
Agamotto built three Sanctums in places of power...
强大的圣殿
where great cities now stand.
这扇门通往香港圣殿
That door leads to the Hong Kong Sanctum.
那扇通往纽约圣殿
That door to the New York Sanctum.
那个 通往伦敦圣殿
That one to the London Sanctum.
就这样
Together...
三个圣殿构成了我们当今世界的保护网
the Sanctums generate a protective shield around our world.
圣殿保护世界
The Sanctums protect the world...
而法师
and we sorcerers...
则保护圣殿
protect the Sanctums.
谁会来捣乱吗
From what?
这说不准 比如说其它空间的生物
Other dimensional beings that threaten our universe.
比如多玛姆
Like Dormammu.
你怎么知道的这个名字
Where did you learn that name?
我从卡里奥斯特罗之书里 怎么了
Ijust read itin The Book of Cagliostro. Why?
多玛姆活在黑暗空间里
Dormammu dwells in the Dark Dimension.
超越了时间
Beyond time.
他是宇宙的吞噬者
He is the cosmic conqueror...
世界的毁灭者
the destroyer of worlds.
具有无穷的能量和超大的野心
A being of infinite power and endless hunger...
他想要入侵所有宇宙
on a quest to invade every universe...
将所有世界全都带入黑暗空间
and bring all worlds into his Dark Dimension.
他最想占领的就是地球
And he hungers for Earth most of all.
那卡西利亚斯偷走的那几页
The pages that Kaecilius stole.
是召唤多玛姆 以及
A ritual to contact Dormammu
从黑暗世界汲取力量的仪式
and draw power from the Dark Dimension.
呃 好吧 好吧
Uh... Okay...
呃 我 我放弃
Urn... I'rn out.
我来这儿可是治疗双手的
I carne here to heal rny hands.
我可不想参加什么神秘的战争
Not to fight in some mystical war.
伦敦
London.
卡西利亚斯
Kaecilius!
不
No!
王 莫度
Wong? Mordo?
布雷克大街177A号
有人吗
Hello?
丹尼尔 他们把你封为这个圣殿的法师
Daniel, I see they made you master of this Sanctum.
那你应该明白
You know what that means?
你将为保卫它而死
That you'll die protecting it.
住手
Stop!
你在卡玛泰基多久了 尊敬的
How long have you been at Kamar-Taj, Mister...
医生
Doctor.
你叫医生
Mister Doctor?
我叫斯特兰奇
It's Strange.
是挺奇的 管你叫什么
Maybe. Who am Ito judge?
你不知道怎么用吧
You don't know how to use that, do you?
什么
What?
噢 别念了
Oh, stop it.
我叫你停下
I said stop it.
这停不下来的 医生先生
You cannot stop this, Mister Doctor.
什么 我都不知道这是什么
I don't even know what 'this' is.
这是结束
It's the end...
也是开始
and the beginning.
结果由多变少 由少归一
The many becoming the few becoming the One.
你要是再跟我这么文绉绉的
If youre not gonna start making sense...
我就还用这个把你嘴封上
I'm just gonna to have to put this thing back on.
说吧 医生先生
Tell me, Mister Doctor...
听着 我的名字叫史蒂芬·斯特兰奇医生
My name is Doctor Stephen Strange.
- 你真是医生 - 是的
- You are a doctor? - Yeah.
作为科学家
A scientist.
你深谙大自然的法则
You understand the laws of nature.
万事万物 生死有命
All things age. All things die.
时光终焉 金乌殆尽
In the end, our sun burns out.
温度逐降 地球灭亡
Our universe grows cold and perishes.
但在黑暗空间
But the Dark Dimension...
这根本不受时间限制
it's a place beyond time.
我看还是得把你嘴封起来
Thats it. I'm putting this thing back on.
这个世界无须灭亡
This world doesn't have to die, doctor.
它可以像许多其它世界一样
This world can take its rightful place alongside so many others...
成为多玛姆的一部分
as part of the One.
非常美丽的部分
The great and beautiful One.
我们将拥抱生命
We can all live forever.
真的吗
Really?
那你从这个新世界空间的乌托邦中能获得什么
What do you have to gain out of this New Age dimensional utopia?
和你一样
The same as you.
和每个人都一样的生命 永恒的生命
The same as everyone. Life. Eternal life.
人们思索着善良与邪恶
People think in terms of good and evil...
而真正的敌人就是时间
when really time is the true enemy of us all.
时间消灭一切
Time kills everything.
那你消灭了的那些人的生命呢
What about the people you killed?
微不足道
Tiny.
那只是浩瀚宇宙中的微小尘埃
Momentary specks within an indifferent universe.
是啊 你看看
Yes. You see.
看看这世界
You see what we're doing.
这个世界还没有回归到正规
The world is not what it ought to be.
每一个人都渴望永生
Humanity longs for the eternal...
想要超越时间 因为我们只是时间的奴隶
for a world beyond time, because time is what enslaves us.
时间是对人类的侮辱
Time is an insult.
死亡是最大的耻辱
Death is an insult.
医生
Doctor...
我并非想统治世界
we don't seek to rule this world.
而是想拯救世界
We seek to save it...
交由万物之主多玛姆来处理这一切
to hand it over to Dormammu,
他才是万物之主
who is the intent of all evolution...
他是万物之源
the why of all existence.
应该是至上尊者保卫这世界
The Sorcerer Supreme defends existence.
你为什么来卡玛泰基 是想开拓思维
What was it that brought you to Kamar-Taj, doctor?
还是想获得
Was it enlightenment?
力量
Power?
你是想来疗伤的 正和大家一样
You came to be healed, as did we all.
卡玛泰基收容可怜的人们
Kamar-Taj is a place that collects broken things.
我们带着治疗的心态而来
We all come with the promise of being healed...
而古一却在玩一些小把戏
and instead The Ancient One gives us parlor tricks.
只有她自己修炼真正的法术
The real magic she keeps for herself.
你不好奇她是怎么活这么长时间的吗
You ever wonder how she managed to live this long?
我 看到了卡里奥斯特罗之书中的仪式
I saw the rituals in The Book of Cagliostro.
那你应该知道
So, you know.
仪式能够给我强大的力量
The ritual gives me the power
战胜古一
to overthrow The Ancient One...
毁灭她的圣殿
and tear her Sanctums down.
释放黑暗空间
To let the Dark Dimension in.
因为多玛姆会大方地赐予永恒的生命
Because what The Ancient One hoards,
而古一
Dormammu gives freely.
是不愿教我的
Life everlasting.
多玛姆不是世界的毁灭者
He's not the destroyer of worlds, doctor.
而是拯救者
He's the savior of worlds.
不 算了吧
No. I mean, come on.
你看看你自己吧
Look at your face.
多玛姆把你变成了杀手
Dormammu made you a murderer.
可想而知 在他的地盘
Just how good can his kingdom be?
你觉得这很好笑
You think thats funny?
不不不 并不是
No, not that.
我笑的是 你的悬戒不见了
What's funny is that you've lost your sling ring.
先生 我能帮你吗
Sir, can I help you?
帕尔默医生 她在哪儿
Doctor Palmer, where is she?
- 先生 我必须 - 她在哪儿
- Sir. We need to get... - Where is she?
她 她在护士站
The nurses station.
克丽丝汀
Christine!
史蒂芬
Stephen?
噢 天呐
Oh, my God.
马上把我送到手术室去 别叫其他人
Get me in an operating theater now. Just you.
快 我没时间了
Now I haven't any time.
发生什么了
What happened?
我被刺伤了 我 心脏填塞
I was stabbed. Cardiac tamponade.
你这穿的是什么东西
What are you wearing?
你的胸腔正常
Chest cavity is clear.
血液流到心包囊里了
No, the blood is in the pericardial sac.
不 不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no.
史蒂芬
Stephen?
挺住 挺住
Come on, come on.
心率过低
往上一点儿
Just a little higher.
别紧张 小心针头
Please be careful with the needle.
史蒂芬
Stephen?
我看到什么了
What am I seeing?
这是我的灵魂
My astral body.
你死了吗
Are you dead?
还没有 但是我快死了
No, Christine. But I am dying.
好吧 好吧
Right.
好吧 往上点儿
Yeah. All right.
好吧
Okay.
噢 喔
Oh, wow.
我从没见过这样的伤口
I've never seen a wound like this.
你是被什么刺伤的
What were you stabbed with?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我现在得消失一会儿
I'm gonna have to vanish now.
你说什么
What?
拜托 别让我死
Keep me alive, will you?
好吧 好吧
Okay.
天呐
Oh, shit.
充电至200焦耳
加油 加油
Come on, come on.
史蒂芬 挺住
Stephen, come on.
再来一次
Hit me again.
别这么吓我
Stop doing that!
增大电压 再来一次
Up the voltage and hit me again.
你已经有心跳了
No, your hearts beating!
听我的
Just do it!
但是我
Oh, my God.
充电至360焦耳
请勿触碰病人 按下电击按钮
天呐 我的天呐
Oh, God! Oh, God!
你还好吧
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah.
好的 好的
Okay.
没想到过了这么久
After all this time...
你突然就这么出现
you just show up here...
从身体里飞了出来
flying out of your body.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
其实我也很想你
I missed you, too, by the way.
我给你写了邮件 但你从来没回我
I wrote you emails, but you never responded.
我为什么要回
Why would I?
克丽丝汀 我真的真的很抱歉
Christine, I am so, so sorry.
我想说你说得对
For all of it. You were right.
我就是混蛋 我对你很不好 伤透了你的心
I was a complete asshole. I treated you so horribly.
你值得遇到更好的人
And you deserved so much more.
你真的是把我吓坏了
Stop. Youre clearly in shock.
我想知道到底发生了什么
What the hell is happening?
你去了哪儿
Where have you been?
发现西医没什么指望以后
Well, after Western medicine failed me...
我就一路向东 最后到加德满都
I headed east, and I ended up in Kathmandu.
加德满都
Kathmandu?
是啊
Yeah.
是鲍勃·塞格尔那首歌吗
Like the Bob Seger song?
那首歌在1975年美丽失败者专辑的A面
1975, Beautiful Loser, side A. Yeah.
我去了一个叫做卡玛泰基的地方
I went to a place called Kamar-Taj...
遇到了一个叫古一的人
and I talked to someone called The Ancient One.'
噢 你真走火入魔了
Oh. So you joined a cult.
不 没有 也不能说没有
No, I didn't. No, not exactly. No.
他们确实教会了我借用未知的力量
They did teach me to tap into powers that I never even knew existed.
没错 你一定走火入魔了
Yeah. That sounds like a cult.
真的不是走火入魔
It's not a cult.
嗯 只有走火入魔的人才会这么说
Well, that's what a cultist would say.
噢 不
Oh, no.
等等 史蒂芬 你到底想上哪儿去
Wait. Stephen, wait. What do you think youre doing?
神魔大会不能迟到
I'm late for a cult meeting.
你不会疯了吧
This is insane.
是啊
Yeah.
- 你到底想去哪儿 - 呃
- Where are you going? - Urn...
不能说实话吗
Can you tell me the truth?
哇哦 一个诡异上古实体
Well, a powerful sorcerer
并且强大得能改变自然法则的法师
who gave himself over to an ancient entity...
正不惜一切手段要杀我
can bend the very laws of physics, tried very hard to kill me.
而我把他困在格林威治村了
But I left him chained up in Greenwich Village...
回去的最好办法就是通过我在清洁间里
and the quickest way back there is through a dimensional gateway...
设置的时空传送门
that I opened up in the mop closet.
好吧 别跟我说了 没关系
Okay. Don't tell me. Fine.
我必须得走了
Really do have to go.
斯特兰奇
Strange!
你没事
You're okay.
相对而言的话 我还好
A relative term. But yeah, I'm okay.
那件魔浮斗篷
The Cloak of Levitation.
它喜欢你
It came to you.
魔浮斗篷可是
No minor feat.
很难得呀
it's a fickle thing.
- 他逃跑了 - 卡西利亚斯
- Hes escaped. - Kaecilius?
是啊
Yeah.
他能够随意折叠空间和物质
He can fold space and matter at will.
你是说他在镜面空间之外折叠物质
He folds matter outside the Mirror Dimension...
在现实世界
in the real world?
是的
Yeah.
- 他有多少人 - 两个
- How many more? - Two.
我把其中一个困在沙漠里了
I stranded one in the desert.
另一个呢
And the other?
尸体还在大厅
His body's in the hail.
德拉姆法师还在那儿
Master Drumm is in the foyer.
他已经被带回卡玛泰基了
He's been taken back to Kamar-Taj.
伦敦圣殿已经崩塌
The London Sanctum has fallen.
只有纽约圣殿和香港圣殿能保护我们
Only New York and Hong Kong remain now...
不受黑暗空间的侵害
to shield us from the Dark Dimension.
你马上去守住纽约圣殿
You defended the New York Sanctum from attack.
那里需要新的法师
With its master gone, it needs another.
斯特兰奇法师
Master Strange.
不
No.
我是斯特兰奇博士
It is Doctor Strange.
不是法师 不是先生
Not Master Strange. Not Mister Strange.
我是斯特兰奇博士
Doctor Strange.
我杀了一个人 我当医生的时候 我发过誓
When I became a doctor, I swore an oath to do no harm.
尽量不让人受到伤害
And I have just killed a man!
可我刚刚就杀了一个人
I'm not doing that again.
我当医生是为了救人 不是为了杀人
I became a doctor to save lives, not take them.
你当医生不过是为了救一个人的性命
You became a doctor to save one life above all others.
你自己的
Your own.
你这是看透我了 是吗
Still seeing through me, are you?
我所见的是事实
I see what I've always seen:
你内心狂妄自大
your over-inflated ego.
你想回到你的妄想之中 掌控一切
You want to go back to the delusion that you can control anything...
甚至死亡
even death...
没人能掌控死亡
which no one can control.
即使伟大的斯特兰奇医生也不行
Not even the great Doctor Stephen Strange.
多玛姆也不行吗
Not even Dormammu?
他可以让人永生
He offers immortality.
人类越害怕死亡 多玛姆就越有生命力
it's our fear of death that gives Dormammu life.
他靠这个活着
He feeds off it.
相当于我们养着他
Like you feed off him?
你还骗我说掌控死亡
You talk to me about controlling death?
我知道你是怎么做到的
Oh, I know how you do it.
我已经看到了卡里奥斯特罗缺失页中的仪式
I've seen the missing rituals from The Book of Cagliostro.
我提醒你注意接下来的措辞 医生
Measure your next words very carefully, doctor.
因为你可能不喜欢听 是吗
Because you might not like them?
因为你可能不知道你到底在说些什么
Because you may not know of what you speak.
他在说些什么
What is he talking about?
我在说关于她的寿命 和她能够永生的秘密
I'm talking about her long life, the source of her immortality.
她从黑暗世界中获取能量
She draws power from the Dark Dimension
从而得到永生
to stay alive.
这不是真的
Thats not true.
我看到了仪式 已经明白了
I've seen the rituals. Worked them out.
我知道你怎么做到的
I know how you do it.
狂热者汇合
Once they regroup...
他们就会卷土重来
the Zealots will be back.
你需要一些人手
You'll need reinforcements.
她不是你么看到的那样
She's not who you think she is.
你没有权利这么说
You don't have the right to say that.
你根本都不知道她肩上的担子有多重
You've no idea the responsibility that rests upon her shoulders.
对 我也根本不想知道
No, and I don't want to know.
你是个懦夫
You're a coward.
就因为我不是杀手
Because I'm not a killer?
狂热者会杀光我们所有人
These Zealots will snuff us all out...
你就眼睁睁地看着 就不能先下手为强吗
and you can't muster the strength to snuff them first?
我刚刚不就下手了吗
What do you think I just did?
你在救你自己的命
You saved your own life!
你的行为就像一条狗一样哀嚎
And then whined about it like a wounded dog.
难道你们就可以问心无愧
Oh, you would have done it so easily?
你根本不知道我经历了些什么
You've no idea the things I've done.
你说得没错
And the answer is yes.
是他们会杀人不眨眼
Without hesitation.
就没有其他的办法了吗
Even if theres another way?
根本没有其他办法
There is no other way.
我看是你缺乏想象
You lack imagination.
不 史蒂芬
No, Stephen.
是你 毫无勇气
You lack a spine.
他们回来了
They're back.
必须有个了断
We have to end this.
上
Now!
斯特兰奇
Strange!
快点下来 战斗
Get down here and fight!
不
No!
镜像空间
The Mirror Dimension.
在这里不会影响到现实世界
You can't affect the real world in here.
看谁笑到最后
Whos laughing now?
你个混蛋
Asshole.
是我
I am.
我拿到了他的悬戒
I've got his sling ring.
他们就跑不了了吧
They can't escape, right?
跑
Run!
他们和黑暗空间的联系
Their connection to the Dark Dimension
增强了他们在镜像空间中的能力
makes them more powerful in the Mirror Dimension.
他们无法影响现实世界 但是他们仍然可以干掉我们
They can't affect the real world, but they can still kill us.
这简直是送死
This wasn't cleverness. It was suicide!
直觉之门
这真是太可笑了
That is hilarious.
这真是个错误
This was a mistake.
噢
Oh!
这是真的
It's true.
她确实从黑暗空间中吸取了能量
She does draw power from the Dark Dimension.
卡西利亚斯
Kaecilius.
那时的我 绝望
I came to you broken...
迷惘 无助
lost, in need.
我信任你 尊你为师 而你却用谎言欺骗了我
Trusted you to be my teacher, and you fed me lies.
我那时是要保护你
I tried to protect you.
防止真相暴露
From the truth?
防止伤害你
From yourself.
我有一位新导师了
I have a new teacher now.
多玛姆是在欺骗你
Dormammu deceives you.
你并没有看到他的真实面目
You have no idea what he truly is.
他那永恒的生命不是天堂 而是地狱
His eternal life is not paradise, but torment.
骗子
Liar.
克丽丝汀
Christine!
这不是在开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me?
噢 天呐
Oh, my God.
她这不是心率失常 而是心肌顿挫
it's not fibrillation. She has a stunned myocardium.
- 是神经性的吗 - 没错
- Neurogenic? - Yes.
谁去拿棉签
Someone get the swabs.
尼克
Nic?
我们得帮她进行颅内减压
We need to relieve the pressure on her brain.
她的心率还在下降
She's still dropping.
她就要死了
Were losing her!
我们得马上给她供氧
We need to increase her oxygen!
帮我准备担架车
I need a crash cart!
她的瞳孔放大了
Her pupils have dilated!
没有反应
No reflexes.
已经读不到任何脑部活动了
Were not reading any brain activity.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
拜托 你要死了
Come on, youre dying!
你必须回到身体里 不然你就没时间了
You have to return to your body now. You don't have time.
时间是相对的
Time is relative.
你自己还没习惯法师的角色
Your body hasn't even hit the floor yet.
我已经花很多年时间
I've spent so many years...
窥视未来
peering through time...
看着这时间点
looking at this exact moment.
我可能挺不过去了
But I can't see past it.
我已经阻止了无数次可怕的事件
I've prevented countless, terrible futures.
但是坏事永远接踵而来
And after each one, there's always another.
所有人都会走到这步
And they all lead here...
停滞不进
but never further.
你觉得自己就这么死去了吗
You think this is where you die.
你想知道你自己的未来吗
You wonder what I see in your future?
不
No.
想
Yes.
我看不到你的未来
I never saw your future.
只能看到可能性
Only its possibilities.
你是一个生性善良的好人
You have such a capacity for goodness.
你出类拔萃
You always excelled...
并不是因为你渴望成功
but not because you craved success...
而是你太害怕失败
but because of your fear of failure.
我是一个成功的医生
Thats what made me a great doctor.
这也是你不够伟大的原因
it's precisely what kept you from greatness.
傲慢和害怕失败
Arrogance and fear still keep you...
使你对最简单
from learning the simplest
也最重要的事情一无所知
and most significant lesson of all.
那是
Which is?
生命的意义不在自我
it's not about you.
当你第一次来找我时
When you first came to me...
你问我是怎么治好乔纳森·潘博恩的
you asked me how I was able to heal Jonathan Pang born.
其实我没有
I didn't.
我没有治愈他 是他自己为自己注入了空间的力量
He channels dimensional energy directly into his own body.
难道他靠法术行走
He uses magic to walk?
一直如此
Constantly.
他曾经面临抉择
He had a choice...
是回归自己的生活
to return to his own life...
还是为更崇高的目标奉献自我
or to serve something greater than himself.
那么我的手能重新治好
So I could have my hands back again?
回到原来的生活
My old life?
当然可以
You could.
但是世界终究会有所遗憾
And the world would be all the lesser for it.
我不愿意从黑暗空间获得能量
I've hated drawing power from the Dark Dimension.
但你知道
But as you well know...
有时人总得打破常规
sometimes one must break the rules...
追求自己认为的那些更高的理想
in order to serve the greater good.
但是莫度不是这样想的
Mordo won't see it that way.
莫度生性固执 不善变通
Mordo's soul is rigid and unmovable...
这是他成长环境造就的
forged by the fires of his youth.
而你灵活多变
He needs your flexibility...
身处逆境 仍能顺势而生
just as you need his strength.
只有你们的优势互补 才有可能战胜多玛姆
Only together do you stand a chance of stopping Dormammu.
我还没准备好
rn not ready.
没人准备好
No one ever is.
我们无法左右世界
We don't get to choose our time.
死亡赋予生命意义
Death is what gives life meaning.
让你知道时光短暂
To know your days are numbered.
去日无多
Your time is short.
我已经准备好迎接死亡了
You'd think after all this time, I'd be ready.
看看吧
But look at me.
我却多么想无限延长这一刻
Stretching one moment out into a thousand...
从而欣赏这美丽的雪景
just so that I can watch the snow.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我不明白你发生了什么
I don't understand whats happening.
我知道
I know.
但是我现在还是得走了
But I have to go away now.
你说过失去双手并不是什么世界末日
You said that losing my hands didn't have to be the end.
但这可能是个开始
That it could be a beginning.
是的
Yeah.
毕竟还有其它拯救生命的方式
Because there are other ways to save lives.
更难的方式
A harder way.
更奇怪的方式
A weirder way.
帕尔默医生 请到急诊室
Doctor Palmer to the ER, please.
Doctor Palmer to the ER.
我不想让你走
I don't want you to go.
别闹了
Stop!
香港
选好你们的武器
Choose your weapon wisely.
没有人可以侵犯圣殿
No one steps foot in this Sanctum.
没有人
No one.
卡西利亚斯
Kaecilius.
你站错队了 王
You're on the wrong side of history, Wong.
她死了
She's dead.
你说得对
You were right.
她并不是我以为的那样
She wasn't who I thought she was.
其实她很矛盾
She was complicated.
她是很矛盾
Complicated?
黑暗空间是个动荡危险的地方
The Dark Dimension is volatile. Dangerous.
万一她被吞噬了呢
What if it overtook her?
她告诉我们不能那么做
She taught us it was forbidden...
可她自己却从中汲取能量 维持了好几百年的寿命
while she drew on its power to steal centuries of life.
她做了认为正确的事
She did what she thought was right.
是时候付出代价了
The bill comes due.
你没看到吗
Don't you see?
她的违禁之举为多玛姆带去了无数狂热者
Her transgressions led the Zealots to Dormammu.
卡西利亚斯更是她酿成的大错
Kaecilius was her fault!
这还不算
And here we are...
我们最终也成了她的棋子
in the consequence of her deception.
世界危在旦夕
A world on fire.
莫度 伦敦圣殿已经崩塌了
Mordo, the London Sanctum has fallen.
纽约圣殿也被袭击了两次
The New York one has been attacked twice.
你知道他们的下一个目标
You know where theyre going next.
香港
Hong Kong.
你曾经对我说 要誓死保卫圣殿
You told me once to fight like my life depended on it...
那一天总会到来
because one day, it might.
今天就是这一天
Well, today is that day.
我需要你和我并肩作战
I cannot defeat them alone.
圣殿已经崩塌了
The Sanctums already fallen.
是黑暗空间
The Dark Dimension.
多玛姆就要来了
Dormammu is coming.
来不及了
it's too late.
没有人能够阻止他
Nothing can stop him.
那可不一定
Not necessarily.
不
No.
咒语生效了
The spell's working.
我们还有一次机会
Weve got a second chance.
不
No!
王
Wang.
打破了自然的法则 我知道
Breaking the laws of nature. I know.
现在可不能停下
Well, don't stop now.
等圣殿修复后
When the Sanctum's restored,
他们会卷土重来
they'll attack it again.
我们必须守护圣殿
Weve got to defend it.
加油
Come on!
振作点儿 斯特兰奇
Get up, Strange.
继续战斗
Get up and fight.
这事该了结了
We can finish this.
你们战胜不了必然发生的事
You can't fight the inevitable.
真是太漂亮了
Isn't it beautiful?
超越时间的世界
A world beyond time.
超越死亡
Beyond death.
超越时间
Beyond time...
斯特兰奇
Strange.
他走了
He's gone.
连他都抛弃了你们 俯首于多玛姆的力量
Even Strange has left you and surrendered to his power.
多玛姆 我是来谈条件的
Dormammu, I've come to bargain.
你是来送死的
You've come to die.
你的世界现在归我了
Your world is now my world...
和其他世界一样
like all worlds.
多玛姆 我是来谈条件的
Dormammu, I've come to bargain.
你是来送死的
You've come to die.
你的世界现在归我了
Your world is now my...
发生了什么
What is this?
是幻觉吗
Illusion?
不 这是现实
No. This is real.
很好
Good.
多玛姆 我是来谈条件的
Dormammu, I've come to bargain.
你 这是什么情况
You've... What is happening?
正如你从你的世界给卡西利亚斯的能力一样
Just as you gave Kaecilius powers from your dimension...
我也从我那儿带了点能力来
I brought a little power from mine.
这是时间
This is time.
无限 循环的 时间
Endless looped time.
你好大的胆子
You dare!
多玛姆 我是来谈条件的
Dormammu, I've come to bargain.
你不可能总这么循环
You cannot do this forever.
事实上 我可以
Actually, I can.
现在不就是这样嘛
This is how things are now.
你和我 困在这同一时刻里
You and me, trapped in this moment...
无限循环
endlessly.
那你就这么无数次死去吧
Then you will spend eternity dying.
没错
Yes.
可地球上的人们会活下来
But everyone on Earth will live.
那你就得受苦了
But you will suffer.
我早习以为常了
Pain's an old friend.
多玛姆
Dormammu...
我是来谈条件的
I've come to bargain.
给我停下
End this!
多玛姆 多玛姆 多玛姆
Dormammu... Dormammu... Dormammu...
你一定会输的
You will never win.
是啊
No...
但我输得起
but I can lose...
反复
again and again...
再反复
and again...
多少次 也不会停止
and again, forever.
你就哪儿也别想去了
And that makes you my prisoner.
不
No!
停下
Stop!
你给我停下
Make this stop!
放我出去
Set me free!
不
No.
我是来谈条件的
I've come to bargain.
你想谈什么条件
What do you want?
带你的信徒们离开地球
Take your Zealots from the Earth.
停止在我们的世界作恶
End your assault on my world.
再也不准回来
Never come back.
你同意
Do it...
我就停止循环
and I'll break the loop.
振作点儿 斯特兰奇
Get up, Strange!
继续战斗
Get up and fight.
这事该了结了
We can finish this.
真是太漂亮了
Isn't it beautiful?
超越时间的世界
A world beyond time.
超越死亡
Beyond death.
你都做了什么
What have you done?
我的条件谈成了
I made a bargain.
这是怎么了
What is this?
噢 这是 这正是你想要的一切
Well, it's everything you've ever wanted.
作为多玛姆生命的一部分
Eternal life as part of the One.
你真的不会喜欢的
Youre not gonna like it.
实话跟你说
Yeah, you know, you really should have
你真的应该偷走那整本书
stolen the whole book because the warnings...
警示就在咒语的后面
The warnings come after the spells.
好笑
Oh, thats funny.
你成功了
We did it.
是啊
Yes.
我们成功了
Yes, we did it.
但是你也算是破坏了
By also violating...
自然法则
the natural law.
你看看周围 都结束了
Look around you. It's over.
你还是觉得这没什么大不了的 对吧
You still think there will be no consequences, Strange?
没有后果
No price to pay?
我们像她一样 打破了规则
We broke our rules, just like her.
迟早会 付出 代价
The bill comes due.
这是注定的
Always!
因果报应
A reckoning.
我不想再继续下去了
I will follow this path no longer.
是啊 好吧
Yeah, okay.
明智的选择
Wise choice.
等你掌握了这个能量
You'll wear the Eye of Agamotto...
就可以佩戴上它了
once you've mastered it's powers.
不过呢
Until then...
最好不要带着这个无限宝石走在大街上
best not to walk the streets wearing an Infinity Stone.
什么石
A what?
你可能有神秘法术的天赋
You might have a gift for the mystic arts,
但是你还需要潜心学习
but you still have much to learn.
古一去世的消息
Word of the Ancient Ones death
很快就会传遍多元宇宙
will spread through the Multiverse.
地球没有至上尊者的守卫
Earth has no Sorcerer Supreme to defend it.
我们得准备好
We must be ready.
时刻准备着
Well be ready.
奇异博士
地球上现在都有法师了
So Earth has wizards now, huh?
茶
Tea?
我不想喝茶
I don't drink tea.
那你喝点什么
What do you drink?
不喝茶
Not tea.
其实我留了一份
So, I keep a watch list...
可能会对这个世界造成威胁的
of individuals and beings from other realms
人类和其他生物的黑名单
that may be a threat to this world.
你那个被收养的弟弟 洛基 就是其中之一
Your adopted brother, Loki, is one of those beings.
他实至名归
Worthy inclusion.
是啊
Yeah.
那你为什么还把他带到纽约来呢
So why bring him here to New York?
说来话长
it's a bit of a long story.
家长里短 乱七八糟的
Family drama, that kind of thing.
我们是来找我父亲的
But we're looking for my father.
那好吧 如果你们 找到了奥丁
Oh, okay. So if you found Odin...
你们就会及时返回阿斯加德吗
youd all return to Asgard promptly?
噢 当然 马上
Oh, yes. Promptly.
好极了
Great!
那我来帮你
Allow me to help you.
需要点什么
Can I help you?
当时你是被他们抬到卡玛泰基来的
They carried you into Kamar-Taj on a stretcher.
现在可大不一样了 潘博恩
Look at you now, Pang born.
莫度
Mordo.
我能为你做点什么
So what can I do for you, man?
我出游了几个月
I've been away for many months now,
无意中听说
and I'vehad a revelation.
法师的真正目的
The true purpose of a sorcerer...
是扭转事物的本来形态
is to twist things out of their proper shape...
偷走法力
stealing power...
违背规则
perverting nature.
就像你一样
Like you.
我没有偷法力 那本来就是
I've stolen nothing. This is my power.
我的
Mine.
法力
Power...
自有其目的
has a purpose.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
因为我终于发现了世界的症结所在
Because I see, at long last, what's wrong with the world.
法师太多了
Too many sorcerers.
敬请期待奇异博士再度回归